[
    {
        "question": "Ic (<em>fremman</em>) #### gu&thorn;e⁠ — I make war",
        "correctAnswer": "fremme",
        "explanation": "Here 'fremman' is in the first person singular form '<em>fremme</em>' because the subject is 'I'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "&THORN;u (<em>nerian</em>) #### &thorn;a cildras⁠ — You save the children",
        "correctAnswer": "nerest",
        "explanation": "Here 'nerian' is in the second person singular form '<em>nerest</em>' because the subject is 'You",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "neriest",
                "explanation": "Remember, the second person singular form of 'nerian' is '<em>nerest</em>' because 'nerian' drops its 'i' in some conjugations"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "He minum l&aelig;rum (<em>hieran</em>) ####⁠ — He listens to my teachings",
        "correctAnswer": "hierð|hierþ",
        "explanation": "Here 'hieran' is in the third person singular form '<em>hierð</em>' because the subject is 'He'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "hiereð|hiereþ",
                "explanation": "Remember, 'hieran' drops the 'e' before a dental fricative"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "We (<em>l&aelig;ran</em>) #### eald Englisc on &thorn;&aelig;m minstere⁠ — We teach Old English in the monastery",
        "correctAnswer": "l&aelig;ra&thorn;",
        "explanation": "Here 'l&aelig;ran' is in the first person plural form '<em>l&aelig;ra&thorn;</em>' as the subject is 'We'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie hergia&thorn; and to scipe (<em>l&aelig;dan</em>) ####⁠ — they harry and carry off the plunder to their ships",
        "correctAnswer": "lædaþ|lædað",
        "explanation": "Here 'l&aelig;dan' is in the third person plural form '<em>lædað</em>' as the subject is 'They'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic (<em>sendan</em>) #### &aelig;rendracan to minum hlaforde⁠ — I sent a messenger to my lord",
        "correctAnswer": "sende",
        "explanation": "Here 'sendan' is in the first person singular past form '<em>sende</em>' because the subject is 'I'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "sendde",
                "explanation": "Remember, when a double d is proceeded by a consonant, the double is reduced to single so the correct form is 'sende'"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Morgensteorran &eth;e we o&eth;re naman &aelig;fensteorra nemnan (<em>hieran</em>) ####⁠ — The morning star which we hear called evening star by another name",
        "correctAnswer": "hierdest",
        "explanation": "Here 'hieran' is in the first person plural past form '<em>hierdest</em>' because the subject is 'We",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie halig God (<em>nerian</em>) ####⁠ — They are saved by holy God",
        "correctAnswer": "neredon",
        "explanation": "Here 'nerian' is in the third person plural past form '<em>neredon</em>' because the subject is 'They'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "neriedon",
                "explanation": "Remember, the third person plural past form of 'nerian' is '<em>neredon</em>' because it drops its 'i' in some conjugations"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "We (<em>fremman</em>) #### swa and Frean hyrde⁠ — We did so and obeyed the lord",
        "correctAnswer": "fremedon",
        "explanation": "Here 'fremman' is in the first person plural past form '<em>fremedon</em>' because the subject is 'We'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie (<em>feran</em>) #### ofer s&aelig;⁠ — They go overseas",
        "correctAnswer": "ferað|feraþ",
        "explanation": "Here 'feran' is in the third person plural form '<em>ferað</em>' because the subject is 'They'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie (<em>feran</em>) #### to Rome⁠ — They went to Rome",
        "correctAnswer": "ferdon",
        "explanation": "Here 'feran' is in the third person plural past form '<em>ferdon</em>' because the subject is 'They'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "&THORN;a (<em>sendan</em>) #### se cyning to &thorn;am flotan Leofsig ealdorman — Then the king sent Alderman Leofsig to the fleet",
        "correctAnswer": "sende",
        "explanation": "Here 'sendan' is in the third person singular past form '<em>sende</em>' because the subject is 'The King'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "sendest",
                "explanation": "Here 'sendan' should be the third person singular past form '<em>sende</em>' because the subject is 'The King'. While &thorn;a resembles the second person <em>'&thorn;u'</em>, it actually means 'then'"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Wyrd oft (<em>nerian</em>) #### unfægne eorl &thorn;onne his ellen deah⁠ — Fate often saves a man not fated to die",
        "correctAnswer": "nereð|nereþ",
        "explanation": "Here 'nerian' is in the third person singular form '<em>nereð</em>' because the subject is 'Wyrd'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "nerieð|nerieþ",
                "explanation": "Remember, the third person singular form of 'nerian' is '<em>nereð</em>' because it drops its 'i' in some conjugations"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic (<em>hieran</em>) #### &thorn;u⁠ — I hear you",
        "correctAnswer": "hiere",
        "explanation": "Here 'hieran' is in the first person singular form '<em>hiere</em>' because the subject is 'I'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic (<em>l&aelig;dan</em>) #### &thorn;one micel here⁠ — I led the great army",
        "correctAnswer": "lædde",
        "explanation": "Here 'l&aelig;dan' is in the first person singular past form '<em>lædde</em>' because the subject is 'I'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "læde",
                "explanation": "Unlike 'sendan', Lædan does not drop double 'd's' because they are proceeded by a vowel. So, here 'l&aelig;dan' is in the first person singular past form '<em>lædde</em>' because the subject is 'I'"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic (<em>l&aelig;ran</em>) #### leden and grecisc⁠ — I taught Latin and Greek",
        "correctAnswer": "lærde",
        "explanation": "Here 'l&aelig;ran' is in the first person singular past form '<em>lærde</em>' because the subject is 'I'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "lærede",
                "explanation": "While <em>l&aelig;ran</em> takes an 'e' in the present first person singular, here 'l&aelig;ran' is in the past tense first person singular form '<em>lædde</em>' because the subject is 'I'"
            }
        ]
    }
]
